{
  "questions":[
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "What purpose does the ngModel directive serve?",
      "questionType":1,
      "options": [
        "Handling HTTP request",
        "Data binding for both input and output",
        "Listening to DOM events",
        "Controlling animation"
      ],
      "answer": "Data binding for both input and output"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "How can you generate a new service using Angular CLI?",
      "questionType":1,
      "options": [
        "ng create service my-service",
        "ng generate service my-service",
        "ng new service my-service",
        "ng add service my-service"
      ],
      "answer": "ng generate service my-service"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "Rank the lifecycle hooks?",
      "questionType":5,
      "options": [
        "ngOnInit()",
        "ngOnChange()",
        "ngDoCheck()",
        "constructor()"
      ],
      "answer": ["constructor()","ngOnChange()","ngOnInit()","ngDoCheck()"]
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "Which Angular decorator is used for making a class a root module?",
      "questionType":1,
      "options": ["@Module()", "@Component()", "@Directive()", "@NgModule()"],
      "answer": "@NgModule()"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "Which is the correct syntax for an Angular Event binding?",
      "questionType":1,
      "options": [
        "{click}=”doSomething()”",
        "on-click=”doSomething()”",
        "(click)=”doSomething()”",
        "click[]=”doSomething()”"
      ],
      "answer": "(click)=”doSomething()”"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "'npm install -g @angular/cli' is used to install Angular CLI globally?",
      "questionType":3,
      "answer": true
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "How do you define a route in Angular?",
      "questionType":4,
      "options": [
        "Using <a> tags",
        "Using the Router service",
        "Using the Routes array",
        "Using the @Route() decorator"
      ],
      "answer": "Using the Routes array"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "Whats the primary purpose of the ngOnInit lifecycle hook in Angular components?",
      "questionType":1,
      "options": [
        "Initialization and data retrieval",
        "Destruction of instances",
        "Manipulation of the views DOM",
        "Handling of user input"
      ],
      "answer": "Initialization and data retrieval"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "selected a prime number?",
      "questionType":2,
      "options": [
        "five",
        "seven",
        "nine",
        "three"
      ],
      "answer": ["five","seven","three"]
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "selected a junkfood?",
      "questionType":2,
      "options": [
        "cakes and biscuits",
        "fast food",
        "vegitables",
        "fruits"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "cakes and biscuits",
        "fast food"
        
      ]
    }
  ]
}
